Share

Share On Facebook

Share On Twitter

Share On Pinterest

Share On LinkedIn

Email

 Copy link

Share My Lesson Privacy Policy
==============================

##### Last updated: 10.4.21

Share My Lesson is a community of educators, and we take the privacy interests of educators very seriously.

If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data, contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://sharemylesson.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Please indicate within the subject heading whether you are a resident of the European Union (“EU”) or the United States (“US”) and the state you reside in.

The American Federation of Teachers, AFL-CIO (hereinafter, AFT) operates sharemylesson.com. It is AFT’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating sharemylesson.com. This Privacy Policy applies strictly to sharemylesson.com.

By clicking “I Agree,” “Finish” or “Accept” during registration, by using sharemylesson.com and/or submitting your personal information to sharemylesson.com, or accepting the collection of information through cookies upon entering the SML website, you consent to our processing of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you do not accept this Privacy Policy, you should not submit your personal data to us, and you may find that you will not be able to make full use of sharemylesson.com.

#### 1\. Website Visitors

Like most website operators, the AFT collects non-personally identifiable information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. AFT’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifiable information is to better understand how visitors to sharemylesson.com use the website. From time to time, the AFT may release non-personally identifiable information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

The AFT also collects potentially personally identifiable information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged-in users and for users leaving comments on sharemylesson.com blogs or discussion forums. The AFT only discloses logged-in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally identifiable information as described below.

#### 2\. Gathering of Personally Identifiable Information

Personally identifiable information, including, without limitation, your contact and other details you supply as part of the registration process will be used by us to authenticate your identity, deal with your inquiries and requests, and to provide you with any services or products you request in connection with sharemylesson.com (including to process your orders and administer your account) and contacting you regarding the administration of any features of the website you have registered to use. Once information is no longer necessary for the purposes it was collected, that information will be deleted. Nevertheless, we may use your personally identifiable information for other purposes, including, without limitation:

* to personalize aspects of sharemylesson.com;
    
* to carry out market research surveys;
    
* to contact you about opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you and to provide you with updates about developments on the sites and information about the products and services we offer;
    
* if required to do so by law; and
    
* for other purposes disclosed at the time you provide us with the personally identifiable information or which are reasonably necessary to provide the website or other related product and/or service requested.

We may use additional information for many purposes, including, without limitation, the following:

* accumulating, reporting and disclosing aggregate (so that no individuals are identified) information in connection with sharemylesson.com and user activity, and for marketing and strategic development purposes (i.e., to identify employment trends across different industries, such as salary averages);
    
* saving certain additional information for your ongoing use of the website;
    
* for the uses described for “Personally Identifiable Information” above; and
    
* for other purposes disclosed at the time you provide us with the additional information, or which are reasonably necessary to provide the website or other related product and/or service requested.

It is your responsibility to ensure that any information submitted as part of the registration process to your user account is accurate and up to date.

In compliance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) from the EU, any personally identifiable information that is collected by SML will be deleted when the collected information is no longer necessary for the purposes stated in this privacy policy. If you are a resident of the EU and invoke your “right to be forgotten,” you must promptly notify SML’s compliance officer of your formal request and state the EU country you reside in.

#### 3\. Aggregated Statistics

AFT may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, AFT may monitor the most popular resources on sharemylesson.com. AFT may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, AFT does not disclose personally identifiable information other than as described below.

#### 4\. Protection of Certain Personally Identifiable Information

AFT discloses potentially personally identifiable and personally identifiable information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (1) need to know that information in order to utilize it in a manner consistent with [AFT’s mission](https://www.aft.org/about/mission) or to provide services available at sharemylesson.com, and (2) have agreed not to disclose it to others. AFT will not sell potentially personally identifiable and personally identifiable information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, AFT discloses potentially personally identifiable and personally identifiable information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when AFT believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of AFT, third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of sharemylesson.com and have supplied your email address, AFT or its affiliated organizations may send you an email to tell you about new information, features, ideas or programs; solicit your feedback; or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with sharemylesson.com or the AFT and its affiliates. If you send us a request (for example, via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. AFT takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally identifiable and personally identifiable information.

#### 5\. Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. AFT uses cookies to help AFT identify and track visitors, their usage of sharemylesson.com, and their website access preferences.

Sharemylesson.com visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using the website, with the drawback that certain features of sharemylesson.com may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

A pop-up window will appear upon entry to the SML website. The window will contain a link to this Privacy Policy and require your consent for the use of cookies on SML’s website. By clicking that you agree to enable cookies, you are confirming your consent for SML’s collection of data associated with cookies. The collection of data associated with cookies will not be used for any purpose other than the stated reasons in this Privacy Policy.

#### 6\. Business Transfers

If AFT, or substantially all of its assets—including sharemylesson.com—were to be merged with another organization or acquired, or in the unlikely event that AFT goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any merged organization or acquirer of AFT may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

#### 7\. Ads

Ads appearing on sharemylesson.com may be delivered to users by advertising partners that permit the use of cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by AFT and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

#### 8\. California Privacy Rights

If you are a resident of the State of California, we provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options such as your right to opt out (which we may sometimes refer to as “unsubscribe”) with respect to use of your personal information by third parties for marketing purposes. Therefore, pursuant to the California Civil Code, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your personal information for marketing purposes during the preceding year. If you are a California resident and wish to request information about how to exercise your third-party disclosure choices, please send a request by email to our Privacy Administrator at [\[email protected\]](https://sharemylesson.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). All requests must be labeled “Your California Privacy Rights” on the email subject line. For all requests, please clearly state that the request is related to “Your California Privacy Rights,” include your name, street address, city, state, ZIP code and email address (your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email) and indicate your preference on how our response to your request should be sent (email or postal mail). We will also accept requests via the telephone 1.800.238.1133 ext. 4504. We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly, or do not have complete information.

#### 9\. Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, AFT may change the sharemylesson.com Privacy Policy from time to time, and at AFT’s sole discretion. AFT encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to the sharemylesson.com Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

#### 10\. Contacting Us Regarding Your Privacy Concerns

If you have any questions about our privacy practices or any of the terms or conditions of this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us as follows:

**Email**: [\[email protected\]](https://sharemylesson.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

OR

**Mail**:

American Federation of Teachers, AFL-CIO

ATTN: Share My Lesson Privacy Concerns

555 New Jersey Ave. N.W., Washington, DC 20001

We will use all reasonable efforts to promptly answer any questions or resolve any concerns regarding your privacy.

Fri, 10/01/2021 - 10:52
